Like I say, welcome brothers and sisters
to another Wednesday question and answer
where we open up with the ten
commandments that God commanded the
whole world to keep. Brother James, yes
sir. And God spake all these words,
saying, I am the Lord thy God, which had
brought thee out of the land of Egypt,
out of the house of bondage. Thou shalt
have no other gods before me. Thou shalt
not make unto thee any graven image, or
any likeness of anything that is in
heaven above, or that is in the earth
beneath, or that is in the water under
the earth. Thou shalt not bow down
thyself to them, nor serve them. For I,
the Lord thy God, am a jealous God,
visiting the iniquity of the fathers,
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation, of them that hate me,
and showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me, and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain, for the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that taketh his name
in vain. Remember the Sabbath day to
keep it holy. Sixth day shalt thou labor
and do all thy work, but the seventh day
is the Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In
it thou shalt not do any work. Thou nor
thy son, nor thy daughter, thy man's
servant, nor thy maid servant, nor thy
cattle, nor thy stranger that is within
thy gates. For in six days the Lord made
heaven and earth, the sea, and all that
in them is, and rested the seventh day.
Wherefore the Lord blessed the Sabbath
day, and hallowed it. Honor thy father
and thy mother, that thy days may be
long upon the land which the Lord thy
God giveth thee. Thou shalt not kill.
Thou shalt not commit adultery. Thou
shalt not steal. Thou shalt not bear
false witness against thy neighbor. Thou
shalt not covet thy neighbor's house.
Thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's
wife, nor as man man's servant, nor as
maid servant, nor his ox, nor his ass,
nor anything that is thy neighbors. I
read Exodus 20:es
1-17. May the Lord add a blessing to the
reading of his word. In Jesus name we
pray. Amen.
Amen. I like to say here on question and
answer, you can ask us a question and
we'll answer it according to the King
James Bible. And if we cannot find the
answer, we will seek further counsel to
bring you an answer at a later time. The
questions that we will not answer are
the vague, the long scripture questions
as well as questions of debate. We are
not here to debate. We are here to
spread the true gospel of Jesus. So
please be as direct as possible with
your questions so we can be as direct
with our answers out of the King James
Bible. No other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also, keep
in mind this is a live stream, so feel
free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just ask
that you keep your questions to a two
scripture maximum. But let me introduce
to you the family that's on the panel
this evening. Brother Julius, good
evening everybody. Brother Dre, good
evening. Brother Jerome, rest in peace.
Brother James, good evening everyone.
Sister Deborah, good evening. Brother
Sean, good evening. And we have Sister
Casey with us as well as the guest
caller. And I'm brother Cornell. Let us
begin with our first question of the
evening. Uh yes, there are several held
over questions that will be answered
first before getting into tonight's Q&A.
Malik Shakira asks, "Are sardines clean
or unclean?"
Sardines are
clean because they must
have fins and scales in order to be
clean. And indeed, they are clean. And
it's a delicacy to a lot of brothers and
sisters, especially today. I know a
brother jump off a speeding train for
some sardines and crackers. But let us
go to Deuteronomy the 14th chapter.
Deuteronomy 14. And let's read because
it'll let us know what's what's clean
for us and what is
not. Deuteronomy 14. Pick it up,
brother. Read that verse 9 and 10 for
me. Okay. Deuteronomy 14:es 9 and 10
says, "These ye shall eat. Of all that
are in the waters, all that have fins
and scales shall ye eat." So sardines
have fins and scales. So you allowed to
eat those. They're small fish, but they
still got fins and scales. Go ahead. And
whatsoever have not fins and scales, you
may not eat, it is unclean unto you. and
whatsoever don't have fins and scales.
You can't eat them. They're unclean unto
you. Like catfish, lobster, shrimp, all
that. But let's go into Leviticus the
11th chapter right quick. Leviticus
11. And when we get there, brother,
we're going to pick it up as at verse
9. Leviticus 11 and nine. Let's pick it
up from another book. Go ahead.
These shall ye eat of all that are in
the waters. Whatsoever hath fins and
scales, in the waters, in the seas, and
in the rivers, them shall ye eat.
Uh-huh. And all that have not fins and
scales in the seas and in the rivers, of
all that move in the waters, and of any
living thing which is in the waters,
they shall be an abomination unto you.
The Lord letting you know he want you to
eat the things that he say you can eat
and don't eat the things that he say you
cannot eat because they'll be
abomination unto you. Last verse,
brother. They shall be even an
abomination unto you. Ye shall not eat
of their flesh, but ye shall have their
carcasses an abomination. Read 12.
whatsoever hath no fins nor scales in
the water, that shall be an abomination
unto you. All right. So, what the Lord
say you can eat, that's what you eat.
And what he say you can't, you cannot
eat. But the sardine does have fins and
scales. So, yes, you can eat that. And
that's all I
got. All right, we'll be moving along to
our next question. Next question.
Christy Watson says, "My understanding
is God gave man seven days and 7,000
years. I heard a message saying God gave
man 12,000 years. I'm confused. Please
confirm."
All right, guest caller. Can you please
help with some of that confusion?
Yes, I can. first thing years. I don't
know where she find out where God who
said God gave man 12,000 years, but I
know where 12,000 years come from. First
thing is, let's go into Genesis the
first
chapter and uh
uh we're going to start at verse
one and read down to verse three.
Okay, that is Genesis 1:es
1-3 which
says go ahead in the beginning God
created the heaven and the
earth and the earth was without form and
void and darkness was upon the face of
the deep and the spirit of God moved
upon the face of the waters and God said
let there be light and there was light.
Go ahead. And God saw that the light
that it was good. And God divided the
light from the darkness. And God called
the light day, and the darkness night,
and the evening and the morning were the
first day.
So now first, so when God uh uh was
reworking the earth and when he create
because it was darkness all over the
earth. So when he created light, that
was the first day. Okay? Now skip down
to verse 27.
Okay? So God created man in his own
image. And the image of God created he
him. Male and female created he them.
So now that is that is when he created
man. Now let's see what day that was.
Get down to uh uh
uh skip down to 30. He also did the
beast too on the same time. Verse 30. Go
ahead. And to every beast of the earth,
and to every foul of the air, and to
everything that creepeth upon the earth,
wherein there is life, I have given
every green herb for meat. And it was
so. And God And God saw everything that
he had made. And behold, it was very
good. And the evening and the morning
were the sixth day.
So now from the first day, which is when
uh uh light was created until the sixth
day when man was
created. Okay. So now on the sixth
day when man was created, there was his
first
day. And what you do is and and God gave
man seven days. So up until man. So what
you'd have to do is you get the right
amount of numbers the years you have to
uh
uh take from
six count to six and then you take man
seven day which his first day started on
the sixth day. So what you'd have to do
is you would have to add uh uh the seven
days to six days of five days rather to
six days and that come up with
12,000 years. From the day that man was
created life is created to man was six
and then so being that the sixth day is
man first day you give him seven. So
seven what's that? Seven and five and
seven is six is is 12 days.
Okay. So now where does that come in?
Let's go and show you where the Lord set
the boundaries of man according to who?
So let's go to Deuteronomy 32nd chapter
and read verse 8.
Okay. Deuteronomy 32 and verse 8 says,
"When the Most High divided to the
nations their inheritance, when he
separated the sons of Adam, he set the
bounds of the people according to the
number of the children of Israel."
Now the bounds means from the day that
uh uh from the first day until the last
day. So from the from the time that God
created light and uh to man was was six
days but being the the first six days is
man's first day he had to add five and
seven which come up with 12. And so the
boundary is the day that he began
setting this earth up for man and the
day that man cease to be stop being man.
That's the end of the seventh day. So
now he said that's why you have a
boundary. That's why each year have 12
months. That's why each day have 12 and
12 24
months. Even when when the Lord came and
picked the apostles, he picked 12 to let
us know that from the time that the life
was created until man's last day as a
man will be total of 12 days, which is
12,000 years. man still have only his
seven days. But when you count the five
days up to his uh uh creation and Adam
the seven, what do you get? 12,000
years. That's all I have to say.
All right, we hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next
question. Next question. Malik Shakur
says, "What if you work on the Sabbath
but are able to find
another, I assume, job, but the pay is
$7 less? Do I still quit?"
Brother Dream, what you say? Yeah,
that's a question Malikite that you
would definitely have to ask answer for
yourself because I really don't know you
know what your income is and will you be
able to meet your bills but let's go to
Exodus the 20th chapter and we going to
start and we going to read Exodus 20
8-11 and this is what the Lord say about
this. Go ahead brother when you get it.
Remember the Sabbath day to keep it
holy. Sixth day shalt thou labor and do
all thy work, but the seventh day is the
Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In it thou
shalt not do any work. Thou nor thy son,
nor thy daughter, thy man's servant, nor
thy maid's servant, nor thy cattle, nor
thy stranger that is within thy gates.
Yes. Go ahead, brother. For in six days
the Lord made heaven and earth, the sea,
and all that in them is, and rested the
seventh day. Wherefore the Lord blessed
the Sabbath day, and hollowed it. So the
Lord gave us the Sabbath day. And one of
the things that he does for us on the
Sabbath Sabbath day, we get fed with the
heritage of Jacob. Let's go look at
that. Isaiah
58:es 13 and 14. Read it when you get
it, brother. Okay. Isaiah 58 13 and 14.
If thou turn away thy foot from the
Sabbath, from doing thy pleasure on my
holy day, and call the Sabbath a
delight, the holy of the Lord,
honorable, and shalt honor him, not
doing thine own ways, nor finding thine
own pleasure, nor speaking thine own
words. Then shalt thou delight thyself
in the Lord, and I will cause thee to
ride upon the high places of the earth,
and feed thee with the heritage of Jacob
thy father, for the mouth of the Lord
has spoken it." Now, this is the word of
God, uh, Brother Malik, but the the
question that you asking is, can you
survive on a $7 pay cut? Can you have
you exhausted all of the possibilities?
Maybe even ask the uh job, will they
give you the Sabbath day off that you
may keep it? Or pray to the Lord that he
give you a job where you don't have to
sacrifice the $7 and you might even get
more pay, but your your heart is in the
right place. And and I pray that the
Lord blesses you with the right answer.
But the word of God is bar none when you
there on the Sabbath day hearing that
word and eating that word. So I I pray
the Lord help you with that process,
brother. That's all I got.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answered their question as we
move on to our next one. Moving on.
Brett Brett has two questions. She says,
"Is it not a sin for men to have
multiple wives and
mistresses? My cousin follows an
Israelite church in Oklahoma. They tried
to use David and Jacob having multiple
wives." That's the first question. And
her second is, "Are the 12 tribes all
black people?"
All right. Yes. caller.
Yeah. Well, you know, Lord allowed
certain things in certain times. You
know, when Adam and Eve, though, the
mother and father of the whole
creation. So, the Lord
allowed brothers uh uh sisters and
brothers to come together and have
babies. And as time go, you had sisters
and brothers God come together and have
babies. And later once the Lord got to a
point he cut that out. And so it was so
uh and uh uh why the Lord let Jacob do
what he did that's between him and uh uh
Jacob. And as far as David's concerned
being a king, I'm going show you that at
some time at point point in time the
Lord terminated that. and let's go and
uh it's just like right now sisters
can't marry brothers. That just don't
happen. But that's the way we started
out. Can't be no other way being that
all of us have the same mother and
father.
However, when it come down to uh uh uh
uh David and Jacob, let's show you
what's written in the book. Let's go to
Deuteronomy the 17th chapter and read
verses 15-1 17.
Okay. Deuteronomy
15-17 says, "Thou shalt and any wise set
him king over thee, whom the Lord thy
God shall choose. One from among thy
brethren shalt thou set king over thee.
Thou mayest not set a stranger over
thee, which is not thy brother. But he
shall not multiply horses to himself,
nor cause the people to return to Egypt
the to end to the end that he should
multiply horses. For as much as the Lord
has said unto you, ye shall henceforth
return no more that
way. Neither shall he multiply wives to
himself, that his heart turn not away,
neither shall he greatly multiply to
himself silver and gold.
Now look, he said, "Neither shall he
multiply." This is the king now. David
was a king. Neither shall he multiply
wise to himself. Anything more than one
is multiplication. Is that correct?
Yeah. Yes, sir.
Now, why the Lord let David do what he
did? That's between him and God. But
this right now, you ain't supposed to
multiply. Why? Let's go into First
Timothy the 3 chapter and read verses 1
and two.
Okay. First Timothy and what was the
chapter?
Third chapter 3
verse one and two. Okay. It says this is
a true s true saying. If a man desire
the office of a bishop he desireth a
good work. A bishop then must be
blameless the husband of one wife.
Viligent, sober, of good behavior given
to hospitality, apt to teach.
Now I say a husband of one wife and be
ready to teach. Now who are we going to
teach? If we walk up and uh try to teach
people and I got four, five wives and
and two, three concubines. Ain't nobody
going to walk away. A ain't nobody going
to deal with
that.
Especially you have uh uh uh you have to
obey the laws of the land. Let's go into
first Peter 2 chapter read verses 13-
15.
Okay. 1 Peter 2 chapter
13-15 says submit yourselves to every
ordinance of man for the Lord's sake
whether it be to the king for the Lord's
sake. For the Lord's sake. See, we
talking about service of God here cuz
people are looking at us. Okay, go ahead
and read. Whether it be to the king as
supreme or unto governors as unto them
that are sent by him for the punishment
of evildoers, and for the praise of them
that do
well. For so is the will of God, that
with welloing ye may put to silence the
ignorance of foolish men.
And and so that's what happened is you
you ought to obey the laws of the land
because if you don't then you going uh
uh then everybody going to be pointing
the finger at you. Look at all them old
so-called Hebrew Israelites. All they
about is four, five wives and a whole
lot of uh uh women on the side. In other
words, they fornicators and and and
adulterers. Yeah.
and and now you going to come up and try
to preach the gospel to somebody with
with them with those kind of odds. No,
no. The laws of this land and the orders
of this land say a man shall have one
wife point
blank. Then again too, you can't use
what David did or what uh uh uh uh
Joseph did. If you're going to use what
somebody I mean so what Jacob did if
you're going to use what somebody else
did then you can use what will happen in
the days of of uh uh uh Adam man can
still go and marry his
sister. So the answer is no. Of course
in this land you can't have but one wife
as far as kings are leaders and uh you
can't have but one wife can't multiply
wife from yourself. And if you want to
be a bishop, this is
a it's bishop is not what man think he
is. They think a bishop is one over a
whole lot of church. You know, bishop is
disciple of the Lord. That's why when uh
uh uh
Judas was uh found guilty, it said it
was written, let his bishop be given to
another. So now you going to be out and
you going to represent
God being like uh uh is written in
Timothy. You have to be a husband of one
wife. But what these brothers doing
that's got all these wives and women on
the side. They can't teach nobody. They
can't bring nobody to God. And we are
chosen to bring people to God. That's
what we are chosen for. We are the
chosen priest of the most high God.
Ain't nobody going to listen to you.
What you doing is sleeping around.
That's what it come down to. Yeah. And
if you going to sleep around, if you
going to do by example, then you may as
well go on in there and sleep with your
sister, right? Don't worry.
As far as as far as the Israelites
concerned, yes, we all
black. There's no such thing as the
white Israelite. If you go back and
remember that Israel, like look at
Moses. Moses passed for Pharaoh's
grandson and Pharaoh was an Egyptian and
all and the Egyptians are black. That's
why when the Greeks looked at him, they
said, "These
people are black." The Greek uh uh word
for black is
athe. And then the Lord liken likened us
to the uh I'm sorry the word black was
misrael
rather. And so Moses and the Israelites
passed through Egyptian. They thought
Moses was the Egyptian and they thought
Paul was an Egyptian. Why? Because he is
black. Moses was a Levite. Paul was a
Benjamite. Then then the Lord lacked us
unto the
Ethiopians. Uh I think it's 9 and seven.
Can somebody see if they can pull it up
right quick?
Jeremiah.
Yeah. Where it said
like where it said, "Are you not as the
children of Ethiopia unto me?"
All right. I'm in search mode for that.
That's Amos 9.
Okay, that's it. Amos 9 and 7, right?
Yeah.
Let me get there.
Amos Amos 9 and7 says, "Are ye not as
the ch as children of the Ethiopians
unto me, oh children of Israel, sayeth
the Lord? Have not I brought up Israel
out of the land of Egypt, and the
Philistines from Captor, and the Syrians
from Kerb?"
Now look, Ethiopians, you don't have one
white ever. That's why the Lord likened
us to Ethiopian because you ain't never
heard of white. Said that he a white or
any other color but black said they
Ethiopian. But the word Ethiopia come
from the word athop which mean burnt
faces or burnt skin. So yes, all of the
Hebrew Israelites are black.
That's all I have to say about both of
them. All right, hope that answered your
question as we continue to move on to
our next. Moving on. Tracy Bowen says,
"My parents were not married when I was
born and I would like to have some
knowledge about only being able to enter
the kingdom only by the 10th
generation."
All right. So her parents weren't
married when she was born. Let's call
her.
Let me go to Deuteronomy the 23rd
chapter. Read verse one and two. Where
it come from? Okay. Deuteronomy the 23rd
chapter 1 and two says, "He that is
wounded in the stones or hath his privy
member cut off shall not enter into the
congregation of the Lord. A bastard
shall not enter into the congregation of
the Lord. Even to his tenth generation
shall he not enter into the congregation
of the Lord.
Read a little more.
An Ammonite or a Moabitete shall not
enter into the congregation of the Lord.
Even to their 10th generation shall they
not enter into the congregation of the
Lord forever.
Now that's a long time. So if that was
talking about the kingdom, then anybody
that's that's harmed or may get
castrated or something like that, he go
to the lake of fire. All of the people
that bastards that don't have that the
parents that was born, all of them would
go to the lake of fire. And all of the
Armmonites and the Moabites would go to
the lake of fire. That ain't got nothing
to do with the God's
kingdoms. Neither salvation. I'mma show
you what everybody have to do. Even
people that the that is uh that is
called you know it's called bastard that
don't have that their parents weren't
married. This is what you have to do. If
you do this you will get salvation.
Let's go into Matthew the 19th chapter
and read 16 and 17.
Matthew
19 16 and 17 says, "And behold, one came
and said unto him,"Good master, what
good things shall I do that I may have
eternal life?" And he said unto him, we
talking eternal life here. I'm talking
on the good in God's kingdom. Go ahead
and read. And he said unto him, why
callst thou me good? There is none good
but one that is God. But if thou will
enter into life, keep the commandments.
Yes, sir.
So now, that's what you have to do. I
don't care if you're Moabitete, whether
your parent was married or not, or
whether you uh uh have castrated or
anything. That's got nothing to do with
eternal life and becoming a a a part of
of of a of God's kingdom and being in
the kingdom. If you keep the
commandments, I don't care what you are,
how you got here, or who you might be.
If you keep the commandments, you going
to be in God's kingdom. Point blank.
Jesus can't
lie. That's all I have to say. Yeah.
That's it. Just run hard and win this
race.
All right, we hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next next
question. Zion asked for you to explain
Hebrew 9 verse
27. Does that mean you get judged as
soon as you die?
Right, Julius? We need a little light on
that question.
Let's go read the Let's go read the
scripture.
Let's go read the scripture. Uh, brother
James, Hebrews
9. Hebrews
9. But we going to pick this up at
24. Hebrews
9 and pick it up at 24.
Okay. For Christ has not entered into
the holy places made with hands, which
are the figures of the true, but into
heaven itself, now to appear in the
presence of God for us. So now we know
what Christ says, "Sit on the right hand
of the father." Now here's our question.
27. Skip down to 27.
And as it is appointed unto men once to
die, but after this the judgment. So
they say this is where they get the term
when you die you're judged right right
away. No, that's not the case. That's
not the case. Let's look at what Job
said. Job the 14th
chapter. Job chapter 14.
Okay.
Pick it up at verse one quickly. Go
ahead.
Man that is born of a woman is a few
days and full of trouble.
So skip all the way down to verse 10.
But man dieth and wasteth away. Yay man
giveth up the ghost. And where is he?
He's not in judgment. Go ahead. As the
waters fall from the sea and the flood
decayth and dryth up. So man, so man
lith down and riseth not till the
heavens be no more. They shall not
heavens be no more. Go ahead. They shall
not awake nor be raised out of their
sleep. So when a person die, where do
they go? Let Job tell you at 13.
Oh that thou wouldest hide me in the
grave. That thou wouldest keep me secret
until thy wrath be passed. that thou
wouldest appoint me a set time and
remember me. Oh, you gota wait till the
in the grave until a set time. Verse 14
quickly. If a man die, shall he live
again? All the all the days of my
appointed time will I wait till my
change come. Oh, you got to wait where?
In the grave. Let's go to 1 Corinthians
the 15th chapter.
Okay, 1 Corinthians the 15th chapter.
Okay, we're going to read verses 22 and
23. Let's look at what Jesus said.
For as in Adam all die, even so in
Christ shall all be made alive. Uh-huh.
But every man in his own order, Christ
the first fruits, afterward they that
are Christ at his coming. Oh, Christ is
already risen. But now nobody gets
nothing until Christ uh return day that
I Christ that's called the dead in
Christ at his return. At his return so
let's look at
uh let's look at let's go to Revelation
where did we read that 23 Christ at his
coming right? Yes. Okay let's go to
Revelation the 20th chapter. Seven
trumpets got to sound before the Lord
come
back. Nobody gets anything.
Revelation 20. We're gonna read 11 to 15
quickly. Go ahead, brother. Now, if you
can get to you can be in the first
resurrection at Christ return that those
that is those that are Christ the first
resurrection, man. Revelation
20 H. Revelation 20. And pick this up
at you can read the whole thing on your
own.
Uh pick it up at verse 6 uh verse 5.
But the rest of the dead live not again
until the thousand years were finished.
This is the first resurrection. These
are the ones who are alive and get their
change at Christ return. You can read
that the whole thing in 1 Corinthians
15th chapter. But the rest of the dead
live not again. That's everybody that's
not in the first resurrection. Verse
six.
Blessed and holy is he that hath pard in
the first resurrection. On such the
second death hath no power, but they
shall be priest of God and of Christ and
shall reign with him a thousand years.
Now a thousand years done pass. Verse
seven quickly. And when the thousand
years are expired, Satan shall be loosed
out of his prison. Now skip uh read
verse 11. You read the whole thing.
Satan goes into the lake of
fire. And now the great white throne
judgment. Here's your judgment. The
great white throne judgment. Verse 11.
And I saw a great white throne and him
that sat on it from whose face the earth
and the heaven fled away. And there was
found no place for him. Cuz that's what
that was for flesh and blood. Go ahead.
And I saw the dead small and great stand
before God. And the books were open. And
another book was open, which is the book
of life. And the dead were judged out of
those things which were written in the
books, according to their works. Go
ahead. And the sea gave up the dead
which were in it. And death and hell
delivered up the dead which were in
them. And they were judged every man
according to their works. Now they were
judged every man according to their
works. Hey, if your works qualify before
God, you became uh uh a part of the God
family. If not, what happens? And death
and hell were cast into the lake of
fire, this is the second death. Go
ahead. And whosoever was not found
written in the book of life was cast
into the lake of fire. So now the
question is uh it is appointed unto for
all men to die and after this is
judgment. when at Christ's return and at
the great white throne judgment a
thousand years later. So no, you don't
get judged to as soon as you die, you go
to the grave until a set time and that
set time is when that seven trumpet
sound or after the thousand years and
you are in the great white throne
judgment. That's all I got on that.
Yeah, that's right, brother. cuz um Job
said he going to lay in the grave and
then he said, "And thou shalt call and I
will answer thee." Yes, sir. All right.
Thank you for that, brother. Hope that
answered their question. As we move on
to our next one, moving on. Kessie Lee
asked you to explain Genesis 9 verse 5.
Genesis 9 and5. Put a little explanation
on it, Brother Julius. Let's go and read
it. Uh, Brother James, I'm there. Go
ahead and read it. And surely your your
blood of your lives will I require at
the hand of every beast will I require
it and at the hand of man and at the
hand of every man's brother will I
require the life of man.
So now
uh read verse six.
Whosoever shedth man's blood by man
shall his blood be shed. For in the
image of God made he man. So he said as
surely your blood of your lives will I
require at the hand of every beast will
I require it and at the hand of man of h
at the hand of every man brother will I
acquire the life of man. So therefore he
going to put judgment in man's hand. If
you shed blood then man is the judge and
man can judge whether you live or die.
Now, let's go to Exodus the 21st chapter
and let's get both of them here. Exodus
21. Exodus 21 and read verse 12. Exodus
21, James and verse 12. Go ahead and
read. He that smiteth a man so that he
die shall be surely put to death. And he
put that in the hands of man. That's why
they give people the death sentence that
is handed down by man. God gave man that
authority to judge man. He that smiteth
a man so that he die because you done
shed blood so that he die shall surely
be put to death. Skip down to verse 28
and 29. 28. Now that we just covered
man, now let's cover the beast. Verse 28
and 29.
If an ox gore a man or a woman that they
die, then the ox shall be surely stoned
and his flesh shall not be eaten. But
the owner of the ox shall be quit. So an
ox or a wild bull done gored a man to
death with his with his horns. So now
the Lord say at the at the hand of the
beast will I require blood. Verse 29.
But if the ox were want to push with his
horn in time past. If he got if he has a
reputation of being a wild and a crazy
bull and pushing with his horn and and
he got w you know he got a bad
reputation. Go ahead. And it had been
testified to his owner and he have not
kept him in but that he have killed a
man or a woman. The ox shall be stoned
and his owner also shall be put to
death. So therefore that is the at the
hand of man will I require blood and at
the hand of the beast will I require
blood. Hey three and four we going to
read that. Is it a sin to hate yourself?
Go ahead. First John 3 and4 says
whosoever committeth sin
yeah I get it. Let's go to Romans 7 and
we gonna look at verse 14 and 15.
Romans 7
14 and 15
says, "For we know that the law is
spiritual, but I am carnal sold under
sin. For that which I do, I allow not.
For what I would that do I not, but what
I hate that I do." or that do I. So if
you carnally minded and you are sold
under sin and the things that you would
do you don't do and the things that you
don't want to do you do and the things
that you hate is what you do. Then I get
the part about
hating yourself in that sense because
you're you are walking around with a
carnal mind and waring. Let's go to
Romans 8 and we're going to look at one
more thing there. Romans 8 and pick it
up at verse
6. For to be carnally minded is death,
but to be spiritually minded is life and
peace. Mhm. Because the carnal mind is
immity against God, for it is not
subject to the law of God, neither
indeed can be. That carnal mind is
trouble and it's a war. But I want to
leave you with this. Let's go to
Proverbs
24 and
16. Okay. Proverbs 24 and
says, "For a just man fallth seven times
and riseth up again, but the wicked
shall fall into mischief." That's the
difference between a man that is waring
and the man that falls and stays in the
mischief. So if you fallen, get back up.
And if you hating
yourself, you know, pray to the Lord to
strengthen you in your walk. Uh Ezekiel
36 and 31 talk about how when you come
into this word, you loathe the things
that you did in your past. So I get that
part. But if you if you have fallen and
not doing what's right, then pray to the
Lord that he strengthen you and separate
yourself from the thing that's defiling
you. That's all I got.
Yep. All right, brother. Thank you. And
nothing wrong with loving yourself
enough to save yourself from this unto
generation. Yes, sir, brother. All
right. Thank you, brother, for that. As
we move on to our next question, next
question. Shady asks, "Why is it a sin
to commit suicide? Why are we not
allowed to kill ourselves?"
All right, brother Jerome, we know thou
should not kill. What you say?
We know um in the Bible, like the
brother was quoting, sin is a
transgression of the law. And it also
reads in the law that thou shalt not
kill. Thou shall not commit murder.
Um,
but this question, I'm going be honest
with you, it's hard for me. I can't
speak for nobody else. It's hard for me.
And I'm going tell you why. Cuz not all
cases of
suicide is the same. You know, you got
some people that commit suicide because
they lost their money in in the stock
market. You know, how do the Lord feel
about that? But then you got some people
that committed suicide
um because they they have mental
illness. How do the Lord feel about
that?
Um, the way the Lord judged those two
scenarios of
suicide, he know best how to make that
judgment call. And to be honest with
you, I don't.
Um, but he going he try to hearts and
the Lord see why you committing suicide
and then the Lord will make a
determination if it's sin or not.
Uh, I don't have no verse on it. If
anybody want to add something, they can.
Yep. Think that was a good explanation
there, brother, cuz everybody got
appeared before the judgment seat of
Christ, right?
And if if you're feeling that, there's a
phone number that you can call and you
should call that number to seek some
help for that because that's not a right
feeling. The Lord
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. That's right, brother.
Yeah. Reach out and see if you can get
you some
help. All right, let's move on to our
next question. Next question. Valencia
asked for explanation
on Romans 4:es 4-6.
Romans 4:es 4 through 6.
Brother Jerome, what you got? Yeah,
let's go read that.
Okay, you get it. Go ahead and read.
Now to him that workketh is the reward
not reckoned of grace, but of debt. But
to him that workketh not, but believeth
on him that is justified, the ungodly,
his faith is counted for righteousness.
Even as David also describeth the
blessedness of the man unto whom God
imputth righteousness without works.
Okay. Uh we understand according to the
Bible, we supposed to keep the
commandments of God, the laws of God,
the ten commandments. All right? But
that's not what he really talking about
in those verses, verses 4-6. What he
talking about is
faith and
grace and how through faith in Jesus and
faith in his
blood your sins are remitted. You know,
uh that's not saying that you're not
supposed to keep the commandments of
God. Okay. So now let's go to
uh Romans the 3
chapter and we gonna pick it up at verse
23 and read it to the 26. Okay.
For all have sinned and come short of
the glory of God, being justified freely
by his grace through the redemption that
is in Christ Jesus, whom God hath set
forth to be a propitiation through faith
in his blood, to declare his
righteousness for the remission of sins
that are passed through the forbearance
of
God. to declare I say at this time his
righteousness that he might be just and
the justifier of him which believeth in
Jesus. See, Paul is trying to get you to
understand, hey, he want you. You got to
keep God's commandments, but you have
a an
advocate. You know, if you sin
inadvertently, you have an advocate.
Okay? Jesus Christ the righteous. And
it's through his righteousness what he
did for us on that cross through faith
in him and faith in his blood. You got
access to the grace where your sins can
be remitted.
Okay. But at but at the same time the
Lord looking for you to
overcome.
Okay. And sin not. All right. So skip
down to verse 31. He's going to
establish that. Go ahead.
Do we then make void the law through
faith? God forbid. Yay, we establish the
law. He telling you, we establish the
law. Okay? So, you need both faith to
get access to the grace for the
remission of your sins. But you got to
keep them commandments if you want to
retain that grace for the remission of
your sins. That that's all I got on.
Well, why don't somebody go into James,
go to James and see what James wrote
when he said fa what what faith without
grace works rather. Yeah,
I got to go read it.
Uh that's in going to be in that James 2
and I guess we can pick it up uh at that
verse 17. James 2 and 17.
Okay. James 2:17 says, "Even so faith,
if it have not works, is dead being
alone. Yay, a man may say, Thou has
faith, and I have works. Show me thy
faith without thy works, and I will show
thee my faith by my works."
Now go to uh uh uh Genesis 22 and see
what the Lord said when he told Abraham
to sacrifice Isaac. 22 and start at
verse 9. When Abraham got ready to when
the Lord told Abraham to go sacrifice
Isaac.
Okay. Genesis 22 and:E9 says, "And they
came to the place which God had told him
of. And Abraham built an altar there,
and laid the wood in order, and bound
Isaac his son, and laid him on the altar
upon the
wood." And Abraham stretched forth his
hand, and took the knife to slay his
son. And the angel of the Lord called
unto him out of heaven, and
said,"Abraham, Abraham." And he said,
"Here am I." And he said, "Lay not thine
hand upon the lad, neither do thou
anything unto him. For now I know that
thou fearest God, seeing that thou hast
not withheld thy son, thine only son,
from
me." So the Lord told Abraham to go and
kill Isaac. And Abraham was going to do
it. And the Lord had to stop him. So
then he told Abraham, "Now I know that
thou fearest God because you will not
withhold thy son, thy only son." How did
he know? He knew because of Abraham's
works that Abraham had faith. That's all
I have to say.
All right. Well, I hope that answered
your question as we move on to our next
one. Uh moving on.
I Chuck Woo says, "Can you please
explain?" Jo uh Joshua
18:10, Leviticus 16 verse 8,
Jonah 1 verse 6. How do you cast lots?
Can we use it in this modern time for
divine directions?
All right. Well, we like to say also
that you added one too many scriptures
there. We say please keep your
scriptures to a two scripture maximum so
we can spread our time best we can
amongst all of our viewers. You got
three there, but let's see how brother
Julius want to share some light. Go
ahead, brother. We just going to deal
with the one Joshua 18 and 10. Brother
Cordell because the other two scriptures
also deal with casting lots. So that's
basically their question. What is uh uh
you ask uh how do you cast lot? Well,
what is casting lot? Casting lots is a
method done in various ways to choose
something or someone for a
purpose. Okay. Casting lots is various
ways in choosing something or someone
for a purpose. You could be drawing
straws. How do you cast lots today? You
can draw straws. You flip a coin. You
you rolling dice. You pulling the slot
machine at the at the uh casino. Um
those are are ways of casting lots to
determine something. uh you could cast a
vote at the ballot box and whoever got
the most votes in Acts the first chapter
they had to cast lots to choose who was
going to take Judas's place who was
going to be the next disciple so it's a
method of choosing something or someone
for a purpose and the rest of your
question is uh can we use um in these
modern times for divine direction I
wouldn't let's go to First of all, let's
read that Joshua 18 and let's read verse
6, James. Joshua 18 and 6. Let's look
what Joshua did when the children of
Israel, they had to portion out some
more tribes, some more land to some
tribes. Verse six. Ye shall therefore
describe the land into seven parts, and
bring the description hither to me, that
I may cast lots for you here before the
Lord our God. So now the Lord is
involved in this right here to determine
who gives what land of the tribes. Verse
10, go ahead. And Joshua cast lots for
them in Shiloh before the Lord. And
there Joshua divided the land unto the
children of Israel according to their
divisions. Uh-huh. And the lot of the
tribe of the children of Benjamin came
up according to their families. and the
coast of their lot came forth between
the children of Judah and the children
of Joseph. So you got uh you you had
uh territory that was given out and
their boundaries but it was done by
casting lots and evidently the Lord
allowed it because uh you don't do
nothing without consulting the Lord. So
that's what Joshua did. Now what we
don't do, we don't cast lots today. We
don't cast lots uh in the sense of
divine. This is the way we do when we
want to go to God for something or to
determine uh whatever we need or who
does this. We pray about it. We take it
to the elders. The elders pray about it
and then but we go to the scriptures.
But if you're an individual, let's go to
John St. John the 14th
chapter. St. John the 14th chapter. We
going to read
12-4. St.
John
14:12-14. Go ahead. Verily, verily, I
say unto you, he that believeth on me,
he that what now? He that believeth on
me, that is key component. He that
believeth on me, you have believed in
God, and you keep his commandments. Go
ahead. The works that I do shall he do
also, and greater works than these shall
he do, because I go unto my father.
And what And whatsoever ye shall ask in
my name, whatsoever you shall ask,
whatever you ask in my name, whatever
you petitioning the Lord for, go ahead.
That will I do that the Father may be
glorified in the Son. Uh-huh. If ye
shall ask anything in my name, I will do
it. If you ask anything in my name, I
will do it. And he told you at 15, if
you love me, keep my commandments. The
Lord love uh for his uh uh his uh
children to call upon him to ask him
which way should I go. That's where your
prayer come in at. James said, "You have
not because you ask not." And you don't
receive it sometime because you ask for
the wrong reasons. So when you're
casting lots, it's just a method of
determining how to choose something or
someone for a purpose. But then the
ultimate thing is pray about it. Go to
the
Almighty because you might be dealing
with a Ouija board and you might be
dealing with fallen fallen spirits and
get yourself in trouble. So do the safe
thing. Keep the commandments. Pray to
God for whatever you want. That's all I
got.
All right. Just wanted to say just
wanted to say if you want divine
direction, read that Bible and do what
God say. That is Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
Get out of the book of the Lord and
read.
Yep. All right. Hope that answered your
question. Our next question. Yes. And
the time is
8:31. MJ asks, "What is laboring for the
Lord? Is it telling others about his
word and keeping his commandments?
All right, brother Dre, share some light
on labor. Yes, it's it's that and some.
But let's go to uh Romans the 12th
chapter and we going to read verses 1
and two
there. Romans 12 1 and two. When you get
it, go ahead, brother James. Okay.
Romans
12 verses 1 and two
says, "I beseech you therefore,
brethren, by the mercies of God, that ye
present your bodies a living sacrifice,
holy, acceptable unto God, which is your
reasonable service." Mhm. and be not
conformed to this world, but be ye
transformed by the renewing of your
mind, that ye may prove what is that
good and acceptable and perfect will of
God. So be transformed by the word of
God, and let it be your direction. and
don't be conformed to this world, but be
transformed by the renewing of your mind
that you may prove what is that good and
acceptable and perfect will of God. And
doing that, you know, and and that
encompasses all those things you said
and more. If anybody would like to add,
go right ahead.
Operating in the fruits of the spirit.
Yes, sir.
All right, hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
Moving on. Malik Shakure asks, "Why
would someone keep the commandments if
they still would be taken to the
wilderness to learn the laws and get a
second chance at the kingdom?"
All right, guest caller.
Well, there ain't no second chance at
the kingdom. You got one chance. But the
whole thing is if you know about the
commandments and don't keep them, you
know what that's called? That is called
rebellion. So now if you don't keep them
when you uh uh
uh uh why you before you go to the
kingdom and you know that the
commandments are there, go to the
wilderness. So now once you go to the
wilderness, you going to have that same
rebellious spirit. Now I'm going show
you what's going to happen. Let's go
into Ezekiel the 20th chapter and we're
going to read from verse 35 to 38.
Okay. Ezekiel 20 verses 35- 38 says,
"And I will bring you into the
wilderness of the people and there will
I plead with you face to
face. Like as I pleaded with your
fathers in the wilderness of the land of
Egypt, so will I plead with you, sayeth
the Lord God.
and I will cause you to pass under the
rod. And I will bring you into the bond
of the covenant, and I will purge out
from among you the rebels, and them that
transgress against me. I will bring them
forth out of the country where they
sjorn, and they shall not enter into the
land of Israel, and ye shall know that I
am the Lord.
So now if you know about the Kamas and
don't keep them now when you go to the
wilderness you going to also rebel and
if you do the Lord's going to kill you
right there. That's what he called
purging out the rebels just like it was
when our forefathers came out of Egypt.
Everybody from 20 years and older died
in the wilderness because except for
Joshua and Caleb because they would not
obey God's commandments.
Now, if you know about the commandments
and you don't keep them now, you gonna
get purged, whoever you are, because you
going to go with that same rebellious
spirit and you will never get into the
land of Israel. You will die in the
wilderness. That's all I have to say.
All right. Hope that answers your
question as we move on to our next one.
Moving on. Melon Natural Journey asks,
"How do you become a member of
IOG? What if you are not located near
any of the locations?"
Well, um, you can become a member. Well,
you can tune in with us every Sabbath
day, first of all, and join in with us.
Let's go to Mark one. Mark one right
quick.
Mark one and let's read verse one and
then let's skip down and read 14 and 15.
Go ahead, brother, when you get there.
The beginning of the gospel of Jesus
Christ, the son of God. Yes.
Now verse 14. Okay. Now after that, John
was put in prison. Jesus came into
Galilee preaching the gospel of the
kingdom of God and saying, "The time is
fulfilled and the kingdom of God is at
hand. Repent ye and believe the gospel."
All right? So, you know, you believe the
gospel, you know, that we bring and we
preach every Sabbath day. And when
you're on board with that, then you can
call the office and ask them to give you
a welcome packet. inside of that and
give you more information on what is
required and you can fill out and you
can become a part of us that way and
also you believe the gospel and you pay
your tithes where you believe the gospel
at because the Lord say why do you spend
your money for that which is not bread
you know a lot of people do that go to
places where they don't believe the
gospel or the gospel is not profiting
them at all even in their learning but
they paying their tithes there but if
you believe what it is that we bring.
Tune in with us every Sabbath. You can
call
7083921320. Ask them to send you a
welcome packet and we will be glad to
welcome you. And um may the Lord add
increased faith to you. That's all I
got. All right, I'm going to leave it
there. We're going to move on to our
next question, Sister Deborah, because I
believe we're going into new territory.
Yes. Uh, we are now into tonight's Q&A
for Wednesday, May the 7,
2025. Jennifer Love asks, "Is it all
right to celebrate Mother's Day?"
Is it all right to celebrate Mother's
Day? Yes, it is. It's a very popular
question we get all the time. You know,
sin is the transgression of the law that
one of the brothers read earlier, but
Mother's Day was just a day that was
celebrated. It's celebrating countries
all around the world first of all, but
that's not why you could celebrate it
per se. But a lady named Anna Jarvis
whose mom passed away, she just wanted
to keep her in memory. And President
Woodro Wilson made Mother's Day a
national holiday. So you can celebrate
Mother's Day if you like. Go get your
mother and take her out and enjoy her.
Enjoy her company. Same thing for
Father's Day. We get that question as
well. They also have sibling day and
uncle day and grandparents day. They
created a whole lot of days. So, hey, I
feel as though I'm a father and a
grandfather. I feel like every day is
Father's Day. Every day is grandfather's
day long as I'm here. But, um, yeah, you
can celebrate Mother's Day and Father's
Day. Nothing wrong with that because
also, let's go and read right quick.
Let's go and read that uh Ephesians 6.
Ephesians
6. And when you get there, brother,
let's pick it up at that verse one. I
believe that's what I want. Ephesians 6
and one.
Okay. Ephesians 6 and1 says, "Children,
obey your parents in the Lord, for this
is right." Yep.
Honor thy father and mother, which is
the first commandment, with promise.
Yep. What's the promise? That it may be
well with thee, and thou mayest live
long on the earth. Yeah. So, you should
honor your mother and your father. And
uh nothing wrong with spending time with
them on this day of Mother's Day or
Father's Day. I mean, hey, thank God
that they still
here. And that's all I
got. And we're gonna move on to our next
question. Sister De. Yes. Next question.
She also asked in Revelations 20
verse4, "What is the mark? Is it the
same as the cross that Sunday churches
uses on the so-called Palm Sunday?"
All right. Why don't we go to that
Revelation 20 that they asking about
here? And uh that scholar would take it
from there dealing with what is the
mark.
Okay. Revelation 20 and4 says, "And I
saw thrones and they that sat upon them,
and judgment was given unto them, and I
saw the souls of them that were beheaded
for the witness of Jesus, and for the
word of God, and which had not worshiped
the beast, neither his image, neither
had received his mark upon their
foreheads or in their hands. And they
lived and reigned with Christ a thousand
years.
Well, the whole thing is you going to
get this. They going to uh u create a
statue of a beast and this false prophet
going to make this beast walk and talk
and going to cause people to receive his
mark. And if you and you won't be able
to buy or sell unless you receive this
mark in your forehead and your right
hand. So now I don't know what that mark
is. Could be a cross. But I know one
thing.
If somebody try to put a mark on you in
that particular time, you don't accept
it in your right hand or in your
forehead. What it is, I don't know. But
whatever it is, they going to try to put
it in your forehead or in your right
hand. So, if you don't let them put no
mark on you for no reason, then you
won't end up with the mark of the beast.
That's all I have to say. All right. I
hope that answers your question as we
move on to our next question.
Next question. Cam Noel asks, "Did David
wear fringes since he was king and
prophet? Didn't he know the law?" And
Psalms
119 10 and 11 is given,
right? Psalms 119 10 and 11. Guess
caller share some light.
Read it.
Psalm 119 10 and 11 says, "With my whole
heart have I sought thee, oh let me not
wander from thy
commandments. Thy word have I hid in
mine heart that I might not sin against
thee." Now the first thing is there was
not there was David's mouth but and
writing but it was not but it was the
words of the Lord. That was Jesus
talking about himself. Now, let me uh uh
uh let me go and show you what I'm
talking about. Go into 2
Samuel 23rd chapter and read verses 1
and two. Okay. 2 Samuel 2 Samuel the
23rd chapter:es 1 and 2 says, "Now these
be the last words of David. David the
son of Jesse said, "And the man who was
raised up on high, the anointed of the
God of Jacob and the sweet psalmist of
Israel said, the spirit of the Lord
spake by me and his word was in my
tongue."
Now, I'm letting you know that when
David made that statement, that was
Jesus talking about
himself. And to give you an example that
uh uh the words that gave those words in
Psalms was uh uh uh was actually the
words of Jesus speaking of himself.
Let's go into Psalms chapter 22 and read
verse one.
Okay. Psalm 22 and verse one says, "My
God, my God, why hast thou forsaken me?
Why art thou so far from helping me and
from the words of my roaring?
Now David wrote that and David uh uh uh
uh said that but that was not David.
Give you a good example. Let's go into
Matthew the 27th chapter read verses 45
and 46.
Okay. Matthew
27 45 and
says, "And about the 9inth hour, Jesus
cried with a loud voice, saying, Eli,
Eli, Lama Sabathani, that is to say, my
God, my God, why hast thou forsaken me?"
So when David made that
statement concerning uh in 119 10 and 11
that was Jesus talking about himself. If
David was so endowed and kept so perfect
by the law that was in him that he would
not have gone and commit adultery with
Bath Sheba and then had her husband
murdered to keep him from finding out.
That's all I have to say. All right.
Hope that answers your question as we
move on with a time check to our next
question. Yes, time is 8:45. Miss Wayey
says, "I have no scripture." Uh, but the
question is, Moses was married two
times. One to the Minion and the other
Ethiopian. Am I right? Did God agree
with these two marriages?
All right.
Because uh
because if you have who said that mar
that that Moses had two
wives, the first wife could have
died and then if a man's wife died that
he can have another wife. So there's
nothing written that I've seen that says
Moses first wife did not die.
Okay. Well, that's all I have to say. If
the woman died, then you can marry
again. So, there ain't nothing to say
that he had them both wives at the same
time.
So, it's most likely being that uh uh uh
Moses was a man of God and God say he's
proven servant is most likely his first
wife had died before he married the
Ethiopian woman.
All right. Thank you.
Thank you for that. Hope that answers
your question as we move on to our next
one. Next one. Harold Peters asks,
"According to scripture,
is cremation of loved ones allowed? And
if it's not, can we be forgiven if done
in ignorance?"
All right. Is cremation allowed, brother
Julius?
There's no place in the book say it's
not. Sin is a transgression of the law.
1 John 3
and4. There's no place in the scripture
says is
not. It is not. Let's go to Genesis
chapter
18. And the definition of cremation is
to burn the body to ashes.
That's the true definition of cremation.
To burn the body to ashes.
They got different ways to do that. They
got a new way by water. And mostly it's
done in a a highly heated
furnace. Genesis, brother James 18. Look
what Abraham said. 26 and 27. Genesis 18
26 and 27.
And the Lord said, "If I find in Sodom
50 righteous within the city, then I
will spare all the place for their
sakes." And Abraham answered and said,
"Behold now, I have taken upon me to
speak unto the Lord, which am but dust
and ashes."
So when you die, you go back to the dust
on a normal funeral and then uh a
quicker way back to the dust or if what
you are is to be burned or cremated,
which is still
ashes. That's why he say I'm but dust
and ashes is a couple more places. But
uh Saul's Saul and his sons were abused
by the Philistines, hung up on the wall,
and they came and gathered his body and
burnt him and his sons and they took him
and buried the bones. But the bottom
line is the Bible does not speak against
cremation. And so you don't have to
worry about uh asking the Lord uh can
you be forgiven because either way it
go, you're coming
back. pray that it be do the right thing
so we can be in the first resurrection.
Yep. That's correct, brother. And if you
happen to cremate your loved one, return
the ashes into the dust to the ground
like the Lord said. Yep.
All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next
moving on. the uh Randy Sims at uh Randy
Sims says the stranger that's sjourned
with Israel, will they get one of those
mansions as well?
The strangers, do they get one of those
mansions as well? Jerome,
let's go um read uh a verse that you're
actually quoting. Let's go to Ezekiel
the 47th
chapter and let's pick it up at 21. Read
to the 23.
Okay. So shall ye divide this land unto
you according to the tribes of Israel.
This Lord return. This is after the Lord
return. and Israel, they going to be
brought back to their own country and
they going to divide the land up among
the tribes. Okay, go ahead. And it shall
come to pass that ye shall divide it by
lot for an inheritance unto you, and to
the strangers that should jointh among
you, which shall be got children among
you. And they shall be unto you as born
in the country among the children of
Israel. They shall have inheritance with
you among the tribes of Israel. Now you
notice in this 20 verse it talked about
be getting children and having children.
Spirit beings ain't going to do that.
All right? So we talking about flesh and
blood people here. Okay. When the Lord
return, you also going to have a first
resurrection when the Lord return. But
those in the first resurrection, they
going to be spirit beings. Okay? So we
talking about flesh and blood in these
verses we read. Keep reading. And it
shall come to pass that in what tribe
the stranger sjouneth there shall ye
give him his inheritance sayeth the Lord
God.
Mhm. So
now they not getting these mansions that
you talking about in your question cuz
the mansions you talking about in your
question are for those that uh come up
in the first
resurrection. The mansions that's in the
uh uh the house of God which is called
New Jerusalem. That's not th those
mansions. Those mansions are not for
flesh and blood beings. Those mansions
are for the spirit beings that come up
in the first
resurrection. No. Uh so let's go to um
Revelations 3 and read verse 11 and 12.
And then we're going to go to the 21st
chapter of Revelation.
Okay. Revelation 3 verse 11 and 12 says,
"Behold, I come quickly. Hold that fast
which thou hast that no man taketh thy
crown. Him that overcomemeth will I make
a pillar in the temple of my God. And he
shall go no more out. And I will write
upon him the name of my God and the name
of the city of my God which is New
Jerusalem which cometh place that got
the that's the place that got the man
the uh the many mansions. It's it's it's
in the place called the city which is
called New Jerusalem that's going to
come down from from God out of heaven
down to this earth. Go ahead. Which
cometh down out of heaven from my God
and I will write upon him my new name.
Okay. Now let's go to Revelations
21. Read about that same city, New
Jerusalem. Chapter 21. 3:1-4.
Okay. And I saw a new heaven and a new
earth, for the first heaven and the
first earth were passed away, and there
was no more sea. And I, John, saw the
holy city, New Jerusalem, coming down
from God, out of heaven, prepared as a
bride adorned for her husband. And I
heard a great voice out of heaven,
saying, "Behold, the tabernacle of God
is with men, and he will dwell with
them, and they shall be his people, and
God himself shall be with them, and be
their God."
And God and God shall wipe away all
tears from their eyes. And there shall
be no more death, neither sorrow nor
crying, neither shall there be any more
pain, for the former things are passed
away. So even when the father's kingdom
come, which we know is dealing with that
new that city called New Jerusalem, and
he said it's going to be with men, but
you just read, but it ain't going to be
no more death. So they might have been
men, but they ain't gonna stay
men. They ain't gonna be no more death.
That mean they bodies got to be changed
into spirit beings, too. But the ones
that make it in that first resurrection,
they going to have one of them mansions
in New
Jerusalem. That's all I got on
the
father's father's kingdom. And if you
read a little further, it'll tell you
and the nations
that are saved. Yeah.
All right. Hope that answers your
question. As
as we are
He want to read that. Um
Okay. That is verse 24. Yeah.
It says verse 24 says, "And the nations
of them which are saved shall walk in
the light of it, and the kings of the
earth do bring their glory and honor
into it."
But I let you know that all of the sons
of Adam, whether they gentile, hamite,
or Shemite,
[Music]
all of the sons of Adam will have
somebody there in the father's kingdom.
But that goes beyond Israel then because
then everybody's God. That's all I have
to say. Yes sir. All
right. Hope that answered your question
as time is a ticking and we are coming
down to our last question or two. Go
ahead Deborah. Yes. Daughter of Judah
asks, "What does John 5 22- 24 mean? Is
Christ the judge over the most high
father in book of Genesis? Who is doing
the creating? Christ or the most high
father?
All right. The one that became the sons
doing the creating. But let's go to
where they said John John 5 and verse
22. And we'll open this up to the panel.
John 5 and verse uh 22.
I got it.
Yes, sir. Okay. It says, "For the Father
judgeth no man, but hath committed all
judgment unto the
Son, that all men should.
Go ahead." That all men should honor the
Son, even as they honor the Father. He
that toucheth not the He that honorth
not the Son honereth not the Father
which has sent him.
Verily, verily, I
Uh-huh. Finish it. Verily, verily, I say
unto you, he that heareth my word, and
believeth on him that sent me hath
everlasting life, and shall not come
into condemnation, but has passed from
death unto life.
Okay. The first thing is uh uh Jesus is
not going to judge over the most high.
Because Jesus is a is is also the most
high. And as far as what have as far as
uh
uh man being judged, let's show you
Jesus is the only one that we have ever
dealt with. Let's go into St. John 5 and
read verse 37.
Okay. John and in and 37 5 and 37 says,
"And the father himself hath sent me,
hath borne witness of me, ye have
neither heard his voice at any time nor
seen his shape."
So now, and that's the case, if you have
never heard his voice at any time or
seen his shape, then the only God you
ever dealt with was Jesus. Go to St.
John the first chapter, read verse 1
through three, and skip down to verse
10.
Okay. It says, "In the beginning was the
word, and the word was with God, and the
word was God. The same was in the
beginning with God. All things were made
by him, and without him was not anything
made that was made."
Now, Revelation 19 chapter will tell you
that when Jesus came, he said, "His name
is called the word of God." So now it
tell you here that Jesus
uh the word was with God and the Jesus
and and the word was God and everything
was created by him and he was in the
world and the world knew it
not and he and he created the world and
the world knew it not. So now Jesus did
the creation. Now let's go into 1
Corinthians the 10th chapter and let you
know who was there with Moses and Israel
10 through1. 1 Corinthians 10 1-3.
Okay. 1 Corinthians 10 verse 1-3 says,
"Moreover, brethren, I would not that ye
should be ignorant how that all our
fathers were under the cloud, and all
passed through the sea, and were all
baptized unto Moses in the cloud and in
the sea, and did all eat the same
spiritual
meat?" And did all drink? And did all
drink the same spiritual drink? for they
drank of that spiritual rock that
followed them. And that rock was Christ.
Now, it was Jesus back there. He's the
one that created everything. He's the
one that that brought Israel through uh
uh uh the Red Sea. He's the one that
gave the commandments. In fact, he is
the one that did it all. 1 Corinthians
15, read 21- 26 and skip down to 28. Go
ahead. Okay. It says, "For for since by
man came death, by man came also the
resurrection of the dead. For as in Adam
all die, even so in Christ shall all be
made
alive. But every man in his own order,
Christ the first fruits, afterward they
that are Christ at his coming."
Go ahead. Then cometh the end when he
shall have delivered up the kingdom to
God, even the Father, when he shall have
put down all rule and all authority and
power. For for he must reign till heath
put all enemies under his feet. The last
enemy that shall be destroyed is death.
Now skip down to verse 28 and read it.
And when all things shall be subdued
unto him, then shall the son also
himself be subject unto him that put all
things under him that God may be all in
all. So Jesus is the one. He created
everything. He come down here and he did
the teaching. Jesus made Israel. And at
the end of it, at the end of the
thousand years after the white throne
judgment, he is going to turn it over to
the father because the father sent him
to do this. Yes. But as far as you
talking about the most
high, let's go into uh this is last
place. Philippians I think the seventh
chap the second chapter and read verse
start at verse five.
Okay, let's see how that go.
Philippians the 2 chapter uh verse 5
says, "Let this mind be in you which was
also in Christ
Jesus who being in the form of God
thought it not robbery to be equal with
God but made himself." Mhm.
Now he's gone back to being in the form
of God. Therefore, God call him God. So
in the form of
God is that mean that he is equal with
God. So there is no most high. Both of
the most high. That's all I have to say.
All right. That's some good light there.
Sister Deborah, one more question and we
are going to call it an evening. Go
right ahead. Yes. Uh be alert. uh says
in Psalms
23:es 4 and 5, could you please shed
light on the valley of shadow of death
and verse five, table prepared before my
enemies? So that's Psalms
23:es 4 and five. Share some light on
those two verses.
All right. Very popular uh prayer. A lot
of people were brought up reciting this.
Go ahead, brother James, when you get
there. Yay. Though I walk through the
valley of the shadow of death, I will
fear no evil, for thou art with me. Thy
rod and thy staff, they comfort me. Thou
preparest a table before me in the
presence of my enemies. Thou anointest
my head with oil. My cup runth over.
Yeah.
Well, for a lot of us, this whole world
is the valley of the shadow of death
because the Lord said, "Our time is
always." You never know when you can get
taken out. But it is the power of God
that is with us and that is supposed to
comfort us. Verse five again, let's open
it up. Go ahead, brother. Thou preparest
a table before me in the presence of my
enemies. Thou anointest my head with
oil, my cup runth
over guess.
Well, the first thing is that Jesus is
doing the talking about himself. Mhm. He
knew he but still he didn't fear. Okay.
That's right. Yep. And then know that he
was going to go back and sit down at the
right hand of the father.
So we prepared to stay before him in the
presence of his enemies. So
now all that's talking about Jesus. Man
can put himself in that position the
same thing. But the ve of the shadow of
death when he knew he had to die for the
sins of the
people. He wasn't afraid.
Yeah. They knew that God was going to
bring him up from the dead and he was
going to sit down at the right hand of
the father
and everybody that aided
him. He said he prepared stay before me
in the presence of my enemies. In other
words, the Lord put him over all his
enemies. That's all I have to say. Yes,
sir. Indeed. All right.
Yep. That was a good question to end our
session on. And we'd like to thank
everybody who tuned in with us from all
around the world. We enjoyed being with
you and we say that we have ran out of
time. And if you submitted a question,
please don't resubmit it. Sister
Deborah, take it, put it into rotation,
and we will answer that question next
week. So until we all come together
again, be safe, be blessed, stay prayed
up, and may the Lord have mercy on us
all. As brother James closes us out.
Our Father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name. Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done in earth as it is in
heaven. Give us this day our daily
bread. And forgive us our debts as we
forgive our debtors. And lead us not
into temptation, but deliver us from
evil. For thine is the kingdom and the
power and the glory forever. In Jesus
name we pray. Amen.
Amen.